A Guide to the Papers of the President of the University of Virginia, Office Administrative Files, 1983-1984
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of the President of the University of Virginia, Office Administrative Files 1983-1984
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
RG-2/1/2.861
This collection consists of 15,000 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Access restrictions may apply to specific student records under the terms of the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (F.E.R.P.A.).
Acquisition Information
This collection was transferred on 1986 June 19.
Scope and Content Information
These files constitute the major record series generated by the president of the University of Virginia. The records consist chiefly of correspondence, but also include reports, minutes, clippings, memoranda, and related papers concerning all areas of business of the president's office.
The papers consist of: general and admistrative committee files, 1983-1984; and, permanent files, 1959-1985.
Permanent records concern: Cyprus; Affirmative Action, Equal Opportunity reports (including Jacobs Report and the Status of Women Faculty Report); Robb's executive orders; Law School; Rare Books library; Board of Visitors; and various individuals, including Mrs. R.M. Jeffress and W.L. Zimmer.
Organization
Series I: General Files, 1983-1984 Boxes 1-27
Series II: Administrative Committees Files, 1983-1984 Boxes 27-28
Series III: Permanent Files, 1959-1985 Boxes 29-37
Series IV: Restricted Material, 1959-1985 Boxes 38
Contents List
- Series I: General Records
  - "A-Al" Miscellaneous 1983-1984 (Box 1)
  - "Am" Miscellaneous--Clinical Psychology Program Accreditation (Am. Psy. Assoc.) 1983-1984 (Box 1)
  - "An-Az" Miscellaneous 1983-1984 (Box 1)
  - Administration--General 1983-1984 (Box 1)
  - Administrative Computing Services 1983-1984 (Box 1)
  - Admissions--General--Minority Enrollment (Nov 9) 1983-1984 (Box 1)
  - Admissions--Law 1983-1984 (Box 1)
  - Admissions--Medical 1983-1984 (Box 1)
  - Afro-American Affairs 1983-1984 (Box 1)
  - Afro-American Affairs--Woodson Institute 1983-1984 (Box 1)
  - Alumni Association--General 1983-1984 (Box 1)
  - American Association of State Colleges and Universities 1983-1984 (Box 1)
  - American Association of University Professors 1983-1984 (Box 1)
  - American Council on Education--Survey Report on 1983 First-Year Students; NCAA 1983-1984 (Box 2)
  - Annual Report 1983-1984 (Box 2)
  - Annual Report--Drafts 1983-1984 (Box 2)
  - Anthropology 1983-1984 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions 1983-1984 (Box 2)
  - Architecture 1983-1984 (Box 2)
  - Art--General 1983-1984 (Box 2)
  - Art--Bayly Museum--Elementary School Teacher Workshop 1983-1984 (Box 2)
  - Asian Studies 1983-1984 (Box 2)
  - Associated Western Universities 1983-1984 (Box 3)
  - Association of American Colleges 1983-1984 (Box 3)
  - Association of American Universities (4 folders) 1983-1984 (Box 3)
  - Association of Virginia Colleges 1983-1984 (Box 4)
  - Astronomy 1983-1984 (Box 4)
  - Athletics--General 1983-1984 (Box 4)
  - Athletics--ACC 1983-1984 (Box 4)
  - Athletics--CFA 1983-1984 (Box 4)
  - Athletics--NCAA 1983-1984 (Box 4)
  - Athletics--NCAA--Clemson 1983-1984 (Box 4)
  - Athletics--Personnel (empty) 1983-1984 (Box 4)
  - Attorney General 1983-1984 (Box 4)
  - Auditor--Internal 1983-1984 (Box 5)
  - Auditor of Public Accounts 1983-1984 (Box 5)
  - "B" Miscellaneous (3 folders) 1983-1984 (Box 5)
  - Biology--General 1983-1984 (Box 5)
  - Business and Finance--General--Perquisites, Faculty Mortgage 1983-1984 (Box 5)
  - Business and Finance--Executive Planning Group 1983-1984 (Box 6)
  - "Ca-Cg" Miscellaneous--Drama Program ("Caplin"), Center for International Affairs 1983-1984 (Box 6)
  - "Ch-Cn" Miscellaneous--China 1983-1984 (Box 6)
  - "Co-Cz" Miscellaneous (1 of 2) 1983-1984 (Box 6)
  - "Co-Cz" Miscellaneous (2 of 2) 1983-1984 (Box 7)
  - Career Planning and Placement 1983-1984 (Box 7)
  - Cavalier Daily 1983-1984 (Box 7)
  - Center for Innovative Technology I (2 folders) 1983-1984 (Box 7)
  - Center for Innovative Technology II (1 of 2) 1983-1984 (Box 7)
  - Center for Innovative Technology II (2 of 2) 1983-1984 (Box 8)
  - Center for Innovative Technology III 1983-1984 (Box 8)
  - Center for Innovative Technology III--Dr. Frank L. Hereford, Jr. (2 folders) 1983-1984 (Box 8)
  - Charlottesville, City of 1983-1984 (Box 8)
  - Chemistry 1983-1984 (Box 8)
  - Civil Rights 1983-1984 (Box 8)
  - Classics 1983-1984 (Box 8)
  - Clinch Valley College--General 1983-1984 (Box 8)
  - College of Arts and Sciences 1983-1984 (Box 8)
  - College Board 1983-1984 (Box 8)
  - Commerce, School of 1983-1984 (Box 9)
  - Community Colleges (empty) 1983-1984 (Box 9)
  - Comptroller (State) 1983-1984 (Box 9)
  - Computing and Communications 1983-1984 (Box 9)
  - Congress 1983-1984 (Box 9)
  - Consortia--General (empty) 1983-1984 (Box 9)
  - Consortia--Central Virginia (empty) 1983-1984 (Box 9)
  - Consortia--Northern Virginia 1983-1984 (Box 9)
  - Consortia--Tidewater 1983-1984 (Box 9)
  - Consortia--Valley (empty) 1983-1984 (Box 9)
  - Consortia--Western 1983-1984 (Box 9)
  - Continuing Education--Oceanic Education, Elderhostel, "Summer on the Lawn" 1983-1984 (Box 9)
  - Council of Presidents (1-2 of 3) 1983-1984 (Box 9)
  - Council of Presidents (3 of 3) 1983-1984 (Box 10)
  - Council of Presidents--Ad Hoc Committee to Study Future of Higher Education 1983-1984 (Box 10)
  - Council of Southern Universities 1983-1984 (Box 10)
  - "D" Miscellaneous (2 folders) 1983-1984 (Box 10)
  - Darden School 1983-1984 (Box 10)
  - Darden Sponsors 1983-1984 (Box 10)
  - Dean's Meeting 1983-1984 (Box 10)
  - Development--General 1983-1984 (Box 10)
  - Drama 1983-1984 (Box 10)
  - "E" Miscellaneous 1983-1984 (Box 11)
  - Economics 1983-1984 (Box 11)
  - Education 1983-1984 (Box 11)
  - Education, School of--Academic Plan 1983-1984 (Box 11)
  - Energy Policies Study Center 1983-1984 (Box 11)
  - Engineering and Buildings 1983-1984 (Box 11)
  - English 1983-1984 (Box 11)
  - Enrollment--General (empty) 1983-1984 (Box 11)
  - Environmental Sciences 1983-1984 (Box 11)
  - Equal Opportunity Office 1983-1984 (Box 11)
  - "F" Miscellaneous 1983-1984 (Box 11)
  - Faculty--General 1983-1984 (Box 12)
  - Faculty of Arts and Sciences 1983-1984 (Box 12)
  - Financial Aid to Students 1983-1984 (Box 12)
  - Food Services 1983-1984 (Box 12)
  - French (empty) 1983-1984 (Box 12)
  - "G" Miscellaneous 1983-1984 (Box 12)
  - General Assembly I (2 folders) 1983-1984 (Box 12)
  - General Assembly II 1983-1984 (Box 13)
  - General Services--State 1983-1984 (Box 13)
  - German 1983-1984 (Box 13)
  - Gifts and Grants (3 folders) 1983-1984 (Box 13)
  - Government and Foreign Affairs 1983-1984 (Box 13)
  - Governmental Relations 1983-1984 (Box 13)
  - Governor 1983-1984 (Box 13)
  - Governor--Administration and Finance 1983-1984 (Box 14)
  - Governor--Commerce and Resources 1983-1984 (Box 14)
  - Governor--Education 1983-1984 (Box 14)
  - Governor--Task Force on Science and Technology 1983-1984 (Box 14)
  - Governor--Transportation and General Safety 1983-1984 (Box 14)
  - Governor--Washington Liaison 1983-1984 (Box 14)
  - Graduate School of Arts and Sciences 1983-1984 (Box 14)
  - Graduate School of Arts and Sciences--Advisory Committee of Career Opportunities 1983-1984 (Box 14)
  - "H" Miscellaneous (2 folders) 1983-1984 (Box 14)
  - 15
  - Higher Education of 1965 (empty) 1983-1984 (Box 15)
  - Higher Education--Title I (empty) 1983-1984 (Box 15)
  - Higher Education--Title III (empty) 1983-1984 (Box 15)
  - Higher Education--Title IX (empty) 1983-1984 (Box 15)
  - History 1983-1984 (Box 15)
  - Honor System--Ad Hoc Faculty Committee in Arts and Sciences on Cheating and Plagiarism; Law School Referendum 1983-1984 (Box 15)
  - House Appropriations 1983-1984 (Box 15)
  - Housing 1983-1984 (Box 15)
  - "I" Miscellaneous 1983-1984 (Box 15)
  - Institute of Government--Virginia Courts Day Forum 1983-1984 (Box 15)
  - Institutional Planning and Studies 1983-1984 (Box 15)
  - Intergovernmental Affairs (empty) 1983-1984 (Box 15)
  - International Students 1983-1984 (Box 15)
  - "J" Miscellaneous 1983-1984 (Box 15)
  - Jefferson, Thomas, Memorial Foundation 1983-1984 (Box 15)
  - Joint Legislative Audit and Review Commission 1983-1984 (Box 16)
  - "K" Miscellaneous 1983-1984 (Box 16)
  - "L" Miscellaneous 1983-1984 (Box 16)
  - Law School--General 1983-1984 (Box 16)
  - Lawn Society--October 1983 Meeting 1983-1984 (Box 16)
  - Legal Advisor 1983-1984 (Box 16)
  - Legislative Services 1983-1984 (Box 16)
  - Library 1983-1984 (Box 16)
  - "Mc" Miscellaneous 1983-1984 (Box 17)
  - "Ma-Me" Miscellaneous--Honors and Awards (see Mary Washington College) 1983-1984 (Box 17)
  - "Mi-Mz" Miscellaneous 1983-1984 (Box 17)
  - Management Analysis and Systems Development 1983-1984 (Box 17)
  - Marine Science 1983-1984 (Box 17)
  - Marine Museum (2 folders) 1983-1984 (Box 18)
  - Mariners' Museum II 1983-1984 (Box 18)
  - Material Management 1983-1984 (Box 18)
  - Mathematics 1983-1984 (Box 18)
  - Medical Center--General 1983-1984 (Box 18)
  - Medical Center--Personnel (empty) 1983-1984 (Box 18)
  - Medical Center--Hospital 1983-1984 (Box 18)
  - Medical Center--Medical School--General--Enrollment Study 1983-1984 (Box 19)
  - Medical Center--Medical School--Personnel 1983-1984 (Box 19)
  - Medical Center--Nursing--General 1983-1984 (Box 19)
  - Medical Center--Nursing--Personnel 1983-1984 (Box 19)
  - Menzies Memorial Trust (empty) 1983-1984 (Box 19)
  - Music 1983-1984 (Box 19)
  - "N" Miscellaneous (2 folders) 1983-1984 (Box 19)
  - National Association of State Universities and Land Grant Colleges (NASLUGC)--General 1983-1984 (Box 19)
  - National Association of State Universities and Land Grant Colleges (NASLUGC)--International Letter 1983-1984 (Box 19)
  - National Science Foundation 1983-1984 (Box 20)
  - Newcomb Hall 1983-1984 (Box 20)
  - "O" Miscellaneous--O'Connor, Sandra Day 1983-1984 (Box 20)
  - Oak Ridge Associated Universities 1983-1984 (Box 20)
  - Omicron Delta Kappa 1983-1984 (Box 20)
  - "P" Miscellaneous (2 folders) 1983-1984 (Box 20)
  - Parking and Transportation 1983-1984 (Box 20)
  - Personnel--General 1983-1984 (Box 20)
  - Personnel and Training--State 1983-1984 (Box 20)
  - Philosophy (empty) 1983-1984 (Box 20)
  - Physical Planning (empty) 1983-1984 (Box 20)
  - Physical Plant 1983-1984 (Box 20)
  - Physics 1983-1984 (Box 20)
  - Planning--Miscellaneous (empty) 1983-1984 (Box 20)
  - Planning--Project Status Reports 1983-1984 (Box 21)
  - Planning and Budget--Capital Outlay 1983-1984 (Box 21)
  - Planning and Budget--State 1983-1984 (Box 21)
  - Planning and Budget--University 1983-1984 (Box 21)
  - Promotions 1983-1984 (Box 21)
  - Provost 1983-1984 (Box 22)
  - Associate Provost for Research 1983-1984 (Box 22)
  - Psychology 1983-1984 (Box 22)
  - Purchases and Supply 1983-1984 (Box 22)
  - "Q" Miscellaneous 1983-1984 (Box 22)
  - "R" Miscellaneous (2 folders) 1983-1984 (Box 22)
  - Real Estate, Risk Management 1983-1984 (Box 22)
  - Registrar 1983-1984 (Box 22)
  - Recommendations-"A-Z" 1983-1984 (Box 22)
  - Religious Studies 1983-1984 (Box 22)
  - ROTC--General 1983-1984 (Box 22)
  - ROTC--Air Force 1983-1984 (Box 22)
  - ROTC--Army 1983-1984 (Box 22)
  - ROTC--Navy 1983-1984 (Box 22)
  - "S" Miscellaneous (1 of 4) 1983-1984 (Box 22)
  - "S" Miscellaneous (2-4 of 4) 1983-1984 (Box 23)
  - Senate--University 1983-1984 (Box 23)
  - Slavic Languages and Literature 1983-1984 (Box 23)
  - Sociology 1983-1984 (Box 23)
  - Southern Association of Colleges and Schools 1983-1984 (Box 23)
  - Southern Association of Land-Grant Colleges and Schools 1983-1984 (Box 23)
  - Space and Energy Management (empty) 1983-1984 (Box 23)
  - Spanish, Italian, and Portuguese 1983-1984 (Box 23)
  - Sponsored Programs 1983-1984 (Box 23)
  - State Council for Higher Education in Virginia (SCHEV) (1 of 3) 1983-1984 (Box 23)
  - State Council for Higher Education in Virginia (SCHEV) (2-3 of 3) 1983-1984 (Box 24)
  - State Council for Higher Education in Virginia (SCHEV)--Notes 1983-1984 (Box 24)
  - State Department of Education 1983-1984 (Box 24)
  - State Fire Marshall 1983-1984 (Box 24)
  - Student Affairs--Major Events Calendar, Organizations and Offices, Part-Time Study, Virginia Progressive Party 1983-1984 (Box 24)
  - Student Council--General 1983-1984 (Box 24)
  - Student Council--Minutes 1983-1984 (Box 25)
  - Summer Session 1983-1984 (Box 25)
  - "T" Miscellaneous (2 folders) 1983-1984 (Box 25)
  - Tayloe Murphy Institute 1983-1984 (Box 25)
  - Travel Invoices 1983-1984 (Box 25)
  - Treasurer 1983-1984 (Box 25)
  - "U" Miscellaneous 1983-1984 (Box 25)
  - U.S. Savings Bonds 1983-1984 (Box 25)
  - United Way 1983-1984 (Box 26)
  - Universities Research Association 1983-1984 (Box 26)
  - University Guides (empty) 1983-1984 (Box 26)
  - University Journal 1983-1984 (Box 26)
  - University Press of Virginia 1983-1984 (Box 26)
  - University Police 1983-1984 (Box 26)
  - University Relations 1983-1984 (Box 26)
  - University Union 1983-1984 (Box 26)
  - "V" Miscellaneous (2 folders) 1983-1984 (Box 26)
  - Virginia Academy of Science 1983-1984 (Box 26)
  - Virginia Quarterly Review 1983-1984 (Box 26)
  - Virginia Student Aid Foundation 1983-1984 (Box 26)
  - "Wa-Wh" Miscellaneous--Gifts, John W. Warner, Washington Dulles Task Force, Weedon Foundation (1 of 2) 1983-1984 (Box 26)
  - "Wa-Wh" Miscellaneous (2 of 2) 1983-1984 (Box 27)
  - "Wi-Wz" Miscellaneous--Gifts; Women's Studies; Woodward, C. Vann 1983-1984 (Box 27)
  - "X-Y-Z" Miscellaneous--Computers in Business Education; Ylvisker, W. 1983-1984 (Box 27)
- Series II: Administrative Committees
  - General 1983-1984 (Box 27)
  - Admissions 1983-1984 (Box 27)
  - Afro-American Affairs Advisory 1983-1984 (Box 27)
  - Algernon Sydney Sullivan Award 1983-1984 (Box 27)
  - Arboretum 1983-1984 (Box 27)
  - Architectural Advisory 1983-1984 (Box 27)
  - Athletic Advisory Council 1983-1984 (Box 27)
  - Bayly Museum 1983-1984 (Box 27)
  - Calendar 1983-1984 (Box 27)
  - Cemetery 1983-1984 (Box 27)
  - Chapel 1983-1984 (Box 27)
  - Chemical and Biological Hazards Safety 1983-1984 (Box 27)
  - Chemical and Biological Hazards Safety--Subcommittee--DNA (empty) 1983-1984 (Box 27)
  - Commencement and Convocations 1983-1984 (Box 27)
  - Commencement and Convocations--Subcommittee--Processions 1983-1984 (Box 27)
  - Commencement and Convocations--Public Occasions 1983-1984 (Box 28)
  - Community Colleges 1983-1984 (Box 28)
  - Computers (empty) 1983-1984 (Box 28)
  - Development Steering (empty) 1983-1984 (Box 28)
  - Education and Employment Opportunities, Obligations and Rights 1983-1984 (Box 28)
  - Energy Conservation 1983-1984 (Box 28)
  - Fraternities and Sororities 1983-1984 (Box 28)
  - Fulbright Grants 1983-1984 (Box 28)
  - Graphics 1983-1984 (Box 28)
  - Gwathmey Award 1983-1984 (Box 28)
  - Housing 1983-1984 (Box 28)
  - International Students 1983-1984 (Box 28)
  - Thomas Jefferson Award 1983-1984 (Box 28)
  - Lectures Page--Barbour and Richard 1983-1984 (Box 28)
  - Library 1983-1984 (Box 28)
  - Master Plan 1983-1984 (Box 28)
  - Names 1983-1984 (Box 28)
  - Proxy Advisory 1983-1984 (Box 28)
  - Radiation Safety 1983-1984 (Box 28)
  - Radiation Safety--Subcommittee--Radioactive Drug Research 1983-1984 (Box 28)
  - Registration 1983-1984 (Box 28)
  - Residential Life 1983-1984 (Box 28)
  - Rhodes Scholarship 1983-1984 (Box 28)
  - ROTC 1983-1984 (Box 28)
  - Scheduling 1983-1984 (Box 28)
  - Scholarships, Grants-in-Aid, Loans and Employment 1983-1984 (Box 28)
  - Security and General Safety 1983-1984 (Box 28)
  - Students Activities 1983-1984 (Box 28)
  - Student Health 1983-1984 (Box 28)
  - Summer 1983-1984 (Box 28)
  - Summer Session 1983-1984 (Box 28)
  - Traffic Appeals 1983-1984 (Box 28)
  - Traffic and Parking 1983-1984 (Box 28)
  - Truman Scholarships 1983-1984 (Box 28)
  - University Committee on Students 1983-1984 (Box 28)
  - University Press 1983-1984 (Box 28)
  - University Union 1983-1984 (Box 28)
  - Virginia Quarterly Review 1983-1984 (Box 28)
  - Virginia Status of University Students 1983-1984 (Box 28)
- Series III: Permanent Files
  - Cyprus (2 folders) 1979 Jan-1983 Mar (Box 29)
  - Cyprus II 1983 Jan-Apr (Box 29)
  - Commonwealth's Equal Opportunity Employer 1978 Mar 8-15 (Box 29)
  - Affirmative Action Plan I (1 of 2) 1976 Apr-1979 Dec (Box 29)
  - Affirmative Action Plan I (2 of 2) 1976 Apr-1979 Dec (Box 30)
  - Affirmative Action II (3 folders) 1980 Jan-1982 Dec (Box 30)
  - Affirmative Action III (1 of 2) 1983 Jan-Jun (Box 30)
  - Affirmative Action III (2 of 2) 1983 Jan-Jun (Box 31)
  - Affirmative Action IV (3 folders) 1983 Jun-1984 Aug (Box 31)
  - Equal Opportunity Reports--"The Black Experience" (Jacobs,, 1974) "Status of Women Faculty" (1974) "Employment Conditions...Non-Academic" (1974) 1974 Aug-1976 Jan (Box 31)
  - Governor Robb's Executive Orders (2 folders) 1982 Jan-1985 Nov (Box 32)
  - Jeffress, Mrs. Robert M. (2 folders) 1970 Jul-1984 Nov (Box 32)
  - Law School (1 of 2) 1976 May-1982 Apr (Box 32)
  - Law School (2 of 2) 1976 May-1982 Apr (Box 33)
  - Library--Rare Books Library (2 folders) 1963 Aug-1985 Jul (Box 33)
  - Visitors Special Committee--Nominations for a President 1973 (Box 33)
  - Board of Visitors--General (1 of 2) 1980 Jan-Jul (Box 33)
  - Board of Visitors--General (2 of 2) 1980 Jan-Jul (Box 34)
  - Board of Visitors--General II 1980 Jul-Dec (Box 34)
  - Board of Visitors--General III (2 folders) 1981 Jan-Mar (Box 34)
  - Board of Visitors--General IV 1981 Mar-Jun (Box 35)
  - Board of Visitors--General V (2 folders) 1982 Jan-Jul (Box 35)
  - Harrison, W. Wright 1968 Apr-1976 Mar (Box 35)
  - Lewis, Lawrence 1959 Dec-1979 May (Box 35)
  - Mattern, Edwin 1970 Mar-1977 Nov (Box 36)
  - McConnell, Joseph 1968 Apr-1978 Feb (Box 36)
  - Patter, William S. 1968 Apr-1979 Jan (Box 36)
  - Santarelli, Donald E. 1970 Mar-1980 (Box 36)
  - Scott, Hugh B. 1971 Mar-1979 Mar (Box 36)
  - Zimmer, William L. (1 of 2) 1972 Mar-1977 Dec (Box 36)
  - Zimmer, William L. (2 of 2) 1972 Mar-1977 Dec (Box 37)
  - Zimmer, William L. II 1978 Jan-Dec (Box 37)
  - Zimmer, William L. Jr. 1978 Dec-1980 Feb (Box 37)
- Series IV: Restricted Material
  - Restricted Material--General Records (2 folders) 1983-1984 (Box 38)
  - Restricted Material--Permanent Files (2 folders) 1959-1985 (Box 38)